Guide to the Cape Verde Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Cape Verde collection
1979-2008
MS 1508
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.77
(4 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to the political, economic, and social conditions in Cape Verde.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection (MS 605); Pamphlet Collection (MS 1351); African Postcard Collection (MS 1507). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to the political, economic, and social conditions in Cape Verde.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Women -- Cabo Verde; Cabo Verde -- Description and travel; Cabo Verde -- Economic conditions; Cabo Verde -- Politics and government; Cabo Verde -- Social conditions; Partido Africano da Independência de Cabo Verde
- Original Accession, 1980-1991
  - Political organizations: journals; newsletters; bulletins; printed material, 1980-1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Organização das Mulheres de Cabo Verde (OMCV): newsletters; journals; bulletins, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Journals: literary and recreational, 1984-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Partido Africano da Independência de Cabo Verde (PAICV): documents of annual congresses, 1988 June-1990 July, 1991 July (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
- Additional Material, 1979-1995; Accession 1995-M-170
  - Chibinho, nos. 1, 2, 1979 Jun, July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Évora, Silvestre, "Renúncia e Abandono", 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Partido Africano da Independência de Cape Verde (PAICV), "Informação," no. 15, 1988 December (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Robson, Paul "Cape Verde: The Challenge of Change", 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Additional Material, 1982-1986; Accession 2010-M-095
  - Podogo: Suplemento Cultural, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Voz do trabalhador, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Unidade e Luta, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Vozdipovo, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional material, 1974-2008; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1974-2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)